Nabeel Ahmad

Mumbai, Maharashtra 400099 nabeel25a25@gmail.com +91 88791 35608

An independent and self-motivated student with proven ability and experienced in Data Science projects with ML and DL Algo. Recognized by professors, colleagues and peers as a personable, dedicated performer who demonstrates innovation, communication and teamwork to ensure quality, timely project completion.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 1998-09-02 Eligible to work in: India

Highest Career Level: 2-5 years experience **Industry:** Analytics, KPO, Research, Analytics

Total years of experience: 0

Work Experience

Junior Quantitative Analyst

IRage Broking Services LLP - Gandhinagar, Gujarat July 2022 to Present

I create everyday trading's profit and loss report also I've to write python scripts for repetitive day's tasks also working on automation for all these.

Student

Imarticus Learning Pvt Ltd - Mumbai, Maharashtra August 2021 to April 2022

Stock Price Prediction using Keras TensorFlow

• This project utilizes Deep Learning models, Long-Short Term Memory (LSTM) Neural Network algorithm, to predict stock prices.

Drug Reviews Sentiment Analysis

- In This Project we are doing Exploratory Data Analysis and Sentiment Analysis on the dataset of drug reviews using Natural Language Processing.
- Applied XG Boost Algorithm and libraries like NumPy, Pandas, NLTK, Matplotlib and Seaborn. Customer Segmentation using RFM Approach
- Performed thorough EDA on the given data of Customers about their purchasing time and date, total quantity bought and their total expense.
- Implemented Feature Engineering for calculating Recency, Frequency and Monetary values of each Customers.
- Used K-Means Clustering for segmentation of the Customers based on their RFM values.

Algo trading

- Data Manipulation of large Futures & Options Dataset.
- Auto login and fetching live data using APIs, coding Technical Indicators building trading strategies and deploying it on AWS server.

Education

Pro Degree with KPMG in Data Science

Imarticus Learning - Mumbai, Maharashtra August 2021 to April 2022

Bachelor of Science in Physics

Mumbai University - Mumbai, Maharashtra July 2015 to May 2018

Intermediate in Maths, Science

Shah Faiz Public School - Ghazipur, Uttar Pradesh April 2013 to March 2015

High school

Shah Faiz Public School - Ghazipur, Uttar Pradesh April 2011 to March 2013

Skills / IT Skills

- Python, R, SQL, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn,
- Machine Learning Supervised and Unsupervised
- Data visualization, Tableau, Matplotlib, seaborn,
- Mathematics, Statistics, Problem Solving,
- Random Forest, Support Vector Machine (SVM), Adaptive. PCA.
- K-Means Clustering, KNN, Time-Series.
- Analytical, Mathematical and logical thinking
- Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, ggplot, Azure, AWS, HTML/CSS.
- · Data analysis skills
- · Microsoft Office
- Data analytics

Languages

- English Fluent
- Hindi Fluent
- Urdu Intermediate

Online Profile

https://github.com/nabzz123

https://medium.com/@nabeel25a25

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nabz-ahm

Certifications and Licenses

Data Science with R and Python

Present

Very detailed course on Data Science in two languages R and Python feom Udemy.

SQL MASTERCLASS: SQL for Data Analytics

Present

Deep course on SQL for Data Analytics with a use case of a large Dataset.